Albert G. Preston papers
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Albert G. Preston papers
1914 - 1965
5 boxes (2.5 linear ft.)
Preston, Albert G., 1879-1965
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Buffalo (N.Y.) Politics and government; Buffalo (N.Y.). Office of the Mayor; Fuhrmann, Louis P, 1868 or 9-1931; Municipal government by commission; New York (State). Commission for the Revision of the Tax Laws; Roesch, Charles E., 1885-1936; Taxation New York(State) Law and legislation
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Former newspaper reporter who came to Buffalo in 1907. Served as executive secretary on Buffalo Commission Charter campaign in 1914; held various posts in Republican city administrations of mayors Roesch and Dowd, including budget director, 1930-1934; from 1930 to 1937 was secretary of the N.Y. State Commission for the Revision of the Tax Laws.
Transcripts of hearings held in Mayor Louis P. Fuhrmann's office for Commission Charter, 1914; transcripts of committee meetings, draft speeches, memoranda, messages and other papers of Mayor Charles E. Roesch, 1930-1934; and papers of the New York State Commission for the Revision of the Tax laws, including transcripts of public hearings and executive sessions, 1930-1931.
Organized into three series: I. Commission Government Charter transcripts, 1914. II. Papers of Mayor Charles E. Roesch administration, 1930-1934. III. New York State Commission for the Revision of the Tax Laws, 1930-1935. Chronological arrangement within series.
- Series I: Commission Government Charter transcripts, 1914 (Box-folder 1.1-1.2)
  - Folder 1: Hearing transcript, March 13, 1914, March 14, 1914
  - Folder 2: Hearing transcript, March 14, 1914
- Series II: Papers of Mayor Charles E. Roesch Administration, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 1.3-2.4)
  - Folder 3: Transcript: meeting of Committee appointed by Mayor, July 23, 1930
  - Folder 4: Transcript: meeting of Committee appointed by Mayor, July 30, 1930
  - Folder 5: Speeches written for Mayor Roesch, 1930-1933
  - Folder 6: Speeches written for Mayor Roesch, undated
  - Folder 7: Miscellaneous speeches [by A. Preston?] ca. 1930-31, 1930 - 1931
  - Folder 8: Conference of Mayors, 1932-1933
  - Folder 1: Mayor Roesch - miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, etc., 1930-1934
  - Folder 2: Mayor Roesch - miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, etc., 1930-1934
  - Folder 3: Mayor Roesch - miscellaneous correspondence, memoranda, etc., 1930-1934
  - Folder 4: Survey of the Government of Monroe County, NY, Part I: Board of Supervisors, 1933
- Series III: New York State Commission for the Revision of the Tax Laws, 1913-1935, 1921 - 1935 (Box-folder 3.1-5.2)
  - Folder 1: Recommendations of the NY State Joint Legislative Committee on Taxation and Retrenchment and of the NY State Taxation Commission, 1921-1929
  - Folder 2: G. William Magly, Observations re Real Estate's Disproportion of the Taxa Burden, Oct. 29, 1930, October 29, 1930
  - Vol. 1: Taxation Bills Introduced in the NY State Legislature, 1913-1930
  - Vol. 2: Public hearings transcripts, Oct. 29-Dec. 2, 1930, October 29, 1930 - December 2, 1930
  - Folder 3: State tax laws - miscellaneous reports, correspondence, etc., 1933-1934
  - Folder 4: Memoranda, July 5 - 12, 1935, July 5, 1935 - July 12, 1935
  - Vol. 1: Transcripts of Executive Sessions, Sept. 3, 1930 - Feb. 3, 1931, September 3, 1930 - February 3, 1931
  - Vol. 2: Transcripts of Executive Sessions, July 1-3, 1931, July 1, 1931 - July 3, 1931
  - Folder 1: Transcripts of Executive Sessions, Sept. 29-30, 1931, September 29, 1931 - September 30, 1931
  - Vol.1: Confidential material submitted to the Commission, 1930-1931
  - Folder 1: Minutes, correspondence, and other materials enclosed in vol.1, 1931-1932
  - Folder 2: Minutes, correspondence, and other material enclosed in vol. 1, 1931-1932